[{
  "questionId": 1,
  "question": "When an activity doesn't exist in memory it is in which state?",
  "options": {
    "A" : "Running State",
    "B" : "Non-existent State",
    "C" : "Starting State",
    "D" : "Loading State"
  },
  "answer": "C"
},
  {
    "questionId": 2,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a state in the lifecycle of a service?",
    "options": {
      "A" : "Running",
      "B" : "Paused",
      "C" : "Starting",
      "D" : "Destroyed"
    },
    "answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 3,
    "question": "What is the function of FaceTime in iPhone?",
    "options": {
      "A" : "Video Calls",
      "B" : "Editing Photos",
      "C" : "Digital Photos",
      "D" : "Taking Videos"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 4,
    "question": "iPhone is a line of Internet and Multimedia-enabled smartphones designed and marketed by ______. ",
    "options": {
      "A" : "Intel",
      "B" : "Apple",
      "C" : "Dell",
      "D" : "IBM"
    },
    "answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 5,
    "question": "Does the iPhone browser support flash applications?",
    "options": {
      "A" : "False",
      "B" : "True"
    },
    "answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 6,
    "question": "The iPhone camera can",
    "options": {
      "A" : "Autofocus",
      "B" : "Make digital photos",
      "C" : "Record videos",
      "D" : "both B & C"
    },
    "answer": "D"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 7,
    "question": "The iPhone has a feature that activates when you rotate the device from portrait to landscape.",
    "options": {
      "A" : "Accelerometer",
      "B" : "Special Sensor",
      "C" : "Rotator",
      "D" : "Shadow detector"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 8,
    "question": "iOS stands for?",
    "options": {
      "A" : "iPhone Operating System",
      "B" : "Inter-network Operating System",
      "C" : "Internet Operating System",
      "D" : "None of the above"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 9,
    "question": "The IDE used in Swift is ______.",
    "options": {
      "A" : "Gas",
      "B" : "Ld",
      "C" : "Xcode",
      "D" : "None of the above"
    },
    "answer": "C"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 10,
    "question": "To create constants in swift we use ______ keyword.",
    "options": {
      "A" : "let",
      "B" : "int",
      "C" : "constant",
      "D" : "var"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 11,
    "question": "Which of the following framework is not used in iOS?",
    "options": {
      "A" : "AppKit Framework",
      "B" : "CoreMotion Framework",
      "C" : "UIKit Framework",
      "D" : "Foundation Framework"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 12,
    "question": "Which of the following iOS frameworks is a commonly used third party library?",
    "options": {
      "A" : "Audiotoolbox.framework",
      "B" : "CFNetwork.framework",
      "C" : "AVFoundation.framework",
      "D" : "AFNetwork.framework"
    },
    "answer": "D"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 13,
    "question": "Flash Applications is supported in iPhone browsers.",
    "options": {
      "A" : "Yes",
      "B" : "No",
      "C" : "It supports flash applications from apple only",
      "D" : "Supports partially"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 14,
    "question": "Which of the following statement is wrong?",
    "options": {
      "A" : "IBAction resolves to void",
      "B" : "IBAction is a type qualifier used by IB to enable connection user experience elements and app code.",
      "C" : "IBAction is a macro defined to denote a method that can be referred to in Interface Builder.",
      "D" : "None of the above"
    },
    "answer": "D"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 15,
    "question": "Which of the following statement is wrong?",
    "options": {
      "A" : "IBOutlet resolves to Id",
      "B" : "IBOutlet is a type qualifier used by Interface Builder as a connection point for sending messages from app code to a user interface element.",
      "C" : "IBOutlet are macro defined to denote a variable  that can be referred to in Interface Builder.",
      "D" : "IBOutlet resolves to nothing"
    },
    "answer": "D"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 16,
    "question": "iOS remote push notification is introduced by apple in which version?",
    "options": {
      "A" : "iOS 3.0",
      "B" : "iOS 6.0",
      "C" : "iOS 2.0",
      "D" : "iOS 4.0"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 17,
    "question": "Multitasking in iOS was introduced in which version?",
    "options": {
      "A" : "iOS 4.0",
      "B" : "iOS 7.0",
      "C" : "iOS 2.0",
      "D" : "iOS 6.0"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 18,
    "question": "Mac OS stands for Macintosh Operating System.",
    "options": {
      "A" : "True",
      "B" : "False"
    },
    "answer": "A"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 19,
    "question": "The programming language developed by Apple Inc. is ______.",
    "options": {
      "A" : "Android",
      "B" : "Swift",
      "C" : "Java",
      "D" : "Python"
    },
    "answer": "B"
  },
  {
    "questionId": 20,
    "question": "Objective-C is the parent language of Swift.",
    "options": {
      "A" : "False",
      "B" : "True"
    },
    "answer": "B"
  }
]
